엄마, 파티가기엔 너무 아파?
Mom? Are you too sick to come to the party?
괜찮아
I'm fine.
그냥 몸을 정리하는거야
You know, it's just my bodyreadjusting, that's all.
바로 갈게, 알았지?
I'll be right there, okay?
어제 정전의 원인에 대해여전히 답변 없음
Still no answers as towhat caused yesterday's blackout,
전기없이 격리된약 6만 가구 이주중
leaving nearly 60,000 homesin the district without power.
I can't imagine.
상상이 안가
빌하고 애들한테서 떨어진지이틀인데, 마치..
I'm away from Bill and the kidsfor two days, and it's like...
어렵지
It's tough.
그래, 네 비밀은 뭐야?
Oh, yeah. So what's your secret?
비크론 많은거
A lot of V-Chrons.
취하지도 않고?
And no alcohol?
아니, 나 금주한지 13개월이야
Nope. I have not had a drink in 13 months.
- 뭐?- 우주에서 DUI는 위험해
- What?- Can't risk getting a DUI in space.
못들어주겠네
I can't wait to hear all about it.
진짜 슬픈 얘기다
You know what, that'sthe saddest story I've
당장 치료 받아야 해
ever heard. We have toremedy that right now.
- 안돼- 그렇지, 한잔 할거니까
- Uh, we can't.- No can'ts, we're doing shots.
여기 의사한테 물어봐
Mm-hmm, well, ask the doctor here.
- 테스트 결과 나오기전엔 안돼- 한잔만
- Not until her tests come back.- One shot.
테스트 나오면
Listen, when her tests come back,
내가 직접
I will personally write her
마가리타 처방할게
a prescription for margaritas.
고맙네
Thank you.
이단, 하지마
Ethan, get off him!
Stop.
다칠거야
You're gonna hurt him.
이단
Ethan.
뭐하니?
Hey. What are you doing?
공을 안주잖아
He wouldn't give me the ball.
그래서 쟤를 눕혔어?
And your solution was to push him down?
이단, 뭐라고 해야지?
Ethan, what do you say?
미안
I'm sorry.
괜찮아
It's okay.
또 이러면, 파티는 없어알겠니?
If you do this again, no moreparty for you. Understand?
정말 미안해요
So sorry, guys.
Yeah. All right, it's fine.
- You okay?- That's okay.
가서 놀자
Let's go play.
당신 지쳤잖아, 놔둬
You've got to be exhausted, go on up.
쓰레기야 버릴수 있어
I can take out the trash.
몰
Moll.
평소대로 돌아온거야, 맞지?
Got to get back to the routine, right?
화났었어
I was angry.
화날때는 어떻해야지?
Is that what you're supposedto do when you get angry?
누굴 때리니?
Hurt someone?
아니
No.
제이크가 진짜로 다치면, 어떤 기분일까?
How do you think you would havefelt if you'd really hurt Jake?
나빠
Bad.
그럴꺼야
Well, I sure hope so.
엄마 화났어?
Mom's mad at me.
아냐, 엄마 화 안났어
No, no. She's not mad.
근데 뭔가 달라
But it's different now. With her.
엄마는 집에 돌아온후적응하는 중이야
Your mom has to get usedto being back home again.
위에 오래 있었잖아
She was up there a long time.
혼자서
All by herself.
평소처럼 느낄려면 좀 있어야 해
It's gonna take a while foreverything to feel normal again,
그렇게 될거야
but it will. I promise.
알았어
Okay.
잘 자거라
Get a good night's sleep.
내일 큰 일 있잖니
We have a big day tomorrow.
나 바꿔줘야 돼
I think I need a flip.
보자
Let me see.
Well, yeah.
You're right.
다 됐다
All set.
사랑한다
I love you.
불 꺼줄래
Will you leave my night-light on?
Sure.
뭐하고 있어?
What brought this on?
꿈꿨어
I had a dream.
꿈에 마커스가 자주 나와?
Do you dream about Marcus much?
점점 덜해
Less and less as I get older.
여전히 생각이 나, 자주
I still think about him.Every now and then.
무슨 생각?
What do you think about?
아직 살아있다면,우리는 없잖아
How if he were still alive,there would be no us.
이단도 없고
No Ethan.
마커스가 죽지 않았다면
Without Marcus dying,
우린 아마 못 만났을거야
we may have never even met.
당신은 그와 함께겠지
Maybe you'd still be with him.
그거 알아?
Well, you know what?
우린 마지막까지
I think we always end up
함께하게 될거야
where we're supposed to.
야스모토 회사에 도착
Approaching Yasumoto Corp.
Hey.
잘 들어
Listen to me.
오늘 너에 대해 얘기할텐데
When I talk about you today...
Hey.
오늘 너에 대해 얘기할텐데
When I talk about you today,
네가 원래 어떻게 프로그램 됐는지
I'm gonna talk a bit abouthow you were originally created
얘기하게 될거야,하지만 그렇다고 해서
for the program, but it doesn't mean
네가 가짜라는 소리가 아니야
I don't see you as real.
- 알겠지?- 아니야
- Okay?- I'm not.
맞아
Well... Yes, you are.
넌 실재야, 나처럼
You exist, just like me.
네 엄마처럼, 알았지?
Just like your mom. Okay?
쥬
Jubes!
토끼
Rabbit!
Oh.
잘하는데
Look at you.
연습했어
He's been practicing.
긴장돼?
You nervous?
어.. 껌이지
Uh... Walk in the park.
그래
Exactly.
잘 모르겠어
I don't even know
어떻게 시작할까
where to begin.
넌 세라핌 스테이션에
You were on the Seraphim Station
13개월간 있었어
for 13 months.
단독 미션이었고?
A solo mission.
그래
Yes.
내내 혼자였고?
You were alone the whole time?
그래서 솔로 미션이라고 하겠지
Well, that's why theycall it a solo mission.
Well...
어.. 솔직히, 이해가 안가
Then I... I honestly d...I don't understand this.
무슨 이해?
Understand what?
내가 알기론, 이번 분기에
I know there weren't any other
다른 ISEA 미션도 없었어
ISEA missions in that quadrant.
Molly,
몰리
거기에서 내가 모르는
was there an emergency
응급상황에 타국 승무원이
that I didn't hear about,
탑승했다던가 그런게 있니?
an international crew that docked?
아니
No.
왜?
Why?
You're pregnant.
너 임신이야
뭐?
What?
You're pregnant.
임신이야
But... But...
가능하지 않아
that's not possible.
젠장
Damn it.
벌금 5달러입니다
Five dollars for the swear jar.
기록해둬
Put it on my tab.
물론이죠
Of course.
연구 데이터 띄우고
Let's run the probe's data deck
샘플의 문제점을 체크해
and check for problems with the samples.
출발전에 어디서 오염된건가
Maybe I contaminated 'emsomehow before they left.
그럴것 같지는 않습니다
I find that unlikely.
친절도 하셔라
Aren't you sweet.
영광입니다
I have my moments.
Molly.
몰리
말해
Go ahead.
비크론이 왔습니다
You have an incoming V-Chron.
베이 1 에 부탁해
Bay 1, please.
베이 1 으로 전송
Sending Bay 1.
카메라 불 켜졌다
The camera's on.
인사해봐
Say hello.
안녕
Hello.
네가 말할래?
You want to tell her?
어서
Go ahead.
나 입학 허가 받았어
I got accepted into school.
오늘 아침에 교장이랑최종 미팅 했어
I had my last meeting withthe principal this morning.
입학식은 당신 돌아올때까지..
We're gonna wait for youto get back for the orie...
벤?
Ben?
솔라 플레어의 간섭이 감지됩니다
I'm detecting interferencefrom a solar flare.
지나가면 다시 플레이 할까요?
Shall I attempt to restart after it passes?
그래
Sure.
재시도..
Attempt to re...
Ben?
- Synced and corrected by oykubuyuk -- www.addic7ed.com
한글자막 Hiqq
설명할게 있어야 할거야
There has to be some kind of explanation.
네가 실수한거 아닐까
How about you made a mistake.
몰리, 네 모든 샘플을각각 두번씩 테스트했어
Molly, I ran every single samplefrom your tether twice.
다른 사람은 없었던게 확실해?
Are you sure there was no one else?
얼마나 물어볼거니?
How many times are you gonna ask me this?
그렇다고 해도,내가 임신못하는거 네가 알잖아
And even if there was,you know I can't get pregnant.
몇년을 노력했었어
We tried for years.
임신촉진제 복용한적은?
Were you taking the fertility drugs?
없어
No. No.
이단 입양전에 끊었어
I... I stopped takingthose way before Ethan.
그냥 가능한 질문들을 하는거야보고서 내야 하니까
I'm just asking every rationalquestion I can think of for the report.
이거 보고서에 넣으면 안돼
You can't put this in the report.
몰리, 이 보고서는스팍스 감독관에게 바로 가는거야
Molly, this report goesstraight to Director Sparks.
거짓말할 수 없어
I can't lie.
거짓말하라는게 아냐
I'm not asking you to lie.
시간을 조금 달라는거야
I'm asking for some time.
친구로서
As my friend.
친구로서, 난 지금 당장
As your friend, I should be admitting you
널 입원시켜야 해
for observation right now.
내가 싫은게 바로 그거야
That's exactly what I'm afraid of.
이제야 가족한테 돌아왔어, 샘
I just got back to my family, Sam.
격리되고 싶지는 않다고
I don't want to end up in quarantine.
존한테 말하기전에알아볼 시간을 좀 달라는거야
Just give me some time tofigure it out before I tell John.
At the Humanichs Project
휴매닉 프로젝트에 있어서
우리는 많은 기계와함께 살아가고 있습니다
we recognize that we livein a world of machines.
대부분의 상호작용은
Most of us interact
우리가 깨어날때부터
with one form or anotherfrom the time we wake up
잠들때까지 지속됩니다
until the time we go to sleep.
로봇에 의한 매일의 활동은
We've outsourced many of ourday-to-day activities to robots
우리 삶을 더 효율적으로 만들죠
that have made our livesway more efficient,
하지만 이런 과정에서가장 중요한 요소가 배제됐습니다
but in the process we've removedthe all-important element
인간 교류
of human connection.
사실상, 우리는 로봇이
Deep down, we all know
실제 인간이 아니란것을 알아요
that robots are not really human.
의료용 보조로봇은
A Medi-Assist bot has
백신투여시 100%의정확도를 보입니다
100% accuracy ratingwhen administering a vaccine,
하지만, 아이들이바늘을 무서워할때
but it cannot comfort a child
안심시켜 주지는 못하죠
who's afraid of the needle.
업무용 안드로이드는은행업무를 볼 수 있지만
A task-android can processyour bank deposit,
여러분이 첫 집을 장만했을때의
but it can't share your joy
기쁨을 나누지는 못합니다
when it helps you buy your first home.
이런 참된 신비로움은 전혀
It turns out the true uncanny valley
보여주질 못합니다이것은 유전적 고리에 의하죠
isn't visual at all. It's thevalley of genuine connection.
휴매닉 프로젝트의 목표는
The goal of the HumanichsProject is to bridge that divide
기계의 인간성을 넣음으로써교류를 이루는 것입니다
by bringing humanity to the machine.
어떻게 하면 될까요?
How are we going to do that?
인공지능을 창조함에 있어서
By creating an artificialintelligence designed
아주 초기부터 연결성을 넣어디자인하는 것입니다
from the very beginning to seek connection.
인터페이스에 0과 1을타이핑하여 프로그램하지만
Programmed not by onesand zeroes that we type
매일의 인간 경험을 주는 것이죠
into interfaces but byday-to-day human experience.
여러분
Ladies and gentlemen,
제 아들을 소개합니다
let me introduce you to my son.
이단
Ethan.
가봐, 토끼
Go get 'em, Rabbit.
Harmon Kryger.
하몬 크래거
내가 합류하기전에 떠났죠
He passed away before I came on board.
가까우셨나요?
Were you close?
네
Yeah.
- 좋은 사람이었어요- 그렇다더군요
- He was a good guy.- So I heard.
우즈 박사님, 고든 켄 입니다
Dr. Woods, I'm Gordon Kern.
새 부감독관이시군요
The new Deputy Director.
나 겠군요
That would be me.
비극적 상황이네요
It's a tragic situation.
가실까요?
Shall we?
솔직히, 박사님의 로그를
I have to be honest. Ispent all weekend preparing
분석하는데 주말을 다 보냈어요
- to grill you on your logs.- Mm.
작업이 완전 철저하시더군요
but your work is incredibly thorough.
여지가 없었어요
Leaves very little left to the imagination.
한가지가 있는데
There was one thing.
- 갭 말이죠- 네, 갭
- The gap.- Yes, the gap.
쉽게 설명되요, 사실..
Well, that's easily explained, actually...
괜찮으시다면,스팍스 감독관님을 기다릴까요?
If you don't mind, we'llwait for Director Sparks.
질문이 있으시답니다
I know he has questions.
아마도 이곳에 있는 모든 분들이
Well, there's something I'm sureeveryone in this room is...
궁금해 할만하지만 무례할까봐
curious about, but we're all either too...
질문 못하고 있는듯 하네요
polite or too embarrassed to ask.
로봇 반란, 맞나요?
The robot uprising, am I right?
어느날 우리를전복하고 노예로 만들어
What's to stop the Humanichsfrom overthrowing us one day
인간 대군주가 되는것은 아닌지?
and enslaving their human overlords?
이런 질문인가요?
Is that the question?
절대 아닙니다
Absolutely nothing.
소유주는 어떻게행동을 제어하고 관리하게 되나요?
How then would an owner controland manage their behavior?
이것은 주인-노예 관계가 아닙니다
It's not a master-slave relationship.
제 파트너와 저의 생각은
My partners and I
기계가 인간화되려면
believe if we want machinesto be more human,
인간 경험을 주어야 하고
we have to give them the human experience.
아이처럼 배우게 하는 것입니다
They have to learn like children learn.
이 휴매닉의 뇌는틀림에서 옮음을 배우고
The Humanichs brainlearns right from wrong,
나쁨에서 좋음을 배웁니다우리가 그러듯이요
good from bad, the same way we all did.
대부분은요
For the most part.
무슨뜻인가요, 대부분은?
What do you mean, for the most part?
어떤 아이인지는 보장이 없다는 거죠
Well, there is no guarantee with any child,
결국 자신의 방식을선택하는건 자유로우니까요
because, in the end, they'refree to choose their own path.
우즈 박사님,저는 페티 도드인데요
Dr. Woods, my name is Femi Dodd.
야스모토씨의 프로그램을보좌하고 있습니다
I chair a number ofprograms for Mr. Yasumoto.
실험 실패시의 과정은 무엇인가요?
What is the protocol inthe event your experiment fails?
정지시키는 응급계획이 있나요?
Do you have an emergencyplan for their shutdown?
힘을 제한하는거요? 당연하죠
To preserve their power? Absolutely.
유휴 모드라고 부릅니다
It's called Interlude Mode.
괜찮지?
- Do you mind?- Excuse me,
잠시, 박사님 미안합니다만
Dr. Woods. I'm sorry.
휴식 모드를 말한게 아니에요
I didn't mean for the resting mode.
종료를 말하는 겁니다
I meant for their termination.
죽이는거요?
To kill them?
그런 말은 고상하지 않지만, 맞아요
That wording is a bit inelegant but yes.
아이가 있으신가요?
Do you have a child?
딸 하나요
I have a daughter.
딸을 죽일 계획이 있나요?
Do you have a plan to kill her?
내 딸은 인간이에요
My daughter's a human being.
차이를 이해 못하겠는데요
I don't understand the difference.
처음부터, 영혼이 있죠
Well, for starters, she has a soul.
도드씨, 존중드립니다만
With all due respect, Ms. Dodd,
영혼이라는 것은 없습니다
there is no such thing as a soul.
영혼이라 부르는 것은
What you call a soul,
삶의 경험에 의한 누적효과입니다
I call a cumulative effectof a lifetime of experience.
따님 뇌 상의 신경학적 작용이죠
Simple information traveling in theneuropathways in your daughter's brain.
박사님, 믿거나 말거나
Believe it or not, Dr. Woods, there are
세상의 많은 사람들은과학만으로 설명할 수 없는
plenty of people in this worldwho still believe that there is
많은것들이 있다고 믿어요
more to us than can beexplained by science.
Well...
그런 사람들이 멍청한거죠
those people are idiots.
- 우즈 박사- 내가 그런 멍청이에요
- Dr. Woods.- I am one of those idiots.
- 미안합니다- 사과를 받아들이죠
- I'm sorry.- I accept your apology.
아뇨, 당신이 멍청이중 하나라서
No, I mean I'm sorry you're one
- 유감이란 거에요- 그만하세요
- of those idiots.- That's enough.
- 어떻게 감히?- 어떻게 감히 나한테
- How dare you?- How dare you ask me
내 아들을 살인하는응급계획을 묻는 겁니까?
do I have a contingencyplan to murder my son.
박사는 지금 세상에 풀려날
And you're asking us for fundingthat can unleash thousands,
수천 수만의 이러한 휴매닉에 대한펀딩을 요청하고 있는 거에요
maybe millions of theseHumanichs on the world.
완전히 적절한 질문이세요
It's a perfectly valid question.
행동의 조정과 제한이 되는지
What sort of controls and restrictions
이자리에서 장담할 수 있나요?
would you put in place to ensurethey behave properly?
답변을 드리죠, 시져씨
And I gave you my answer, Mr. Segers.
절대 안됩니다
Absolutely none.
보안 및 생명유지 시스템은
The security and life support systems
대부분 즉시 복구됐어요
were back online almost immediately,
하지만 통신 시스템은
but the communication system
약 13시간동안 다운상태였죠
stayed down for approximately 13 hours.
거기 로그에 나오듯이,전 대부분의 시간을
As it says in my log book there,I spent most of that time
시스템을 복구하는데 썼지만
trying to get the systemup and running again, but,
불행히, 잘 안됐어요
unfortunately, I was unsuccessful.
그리고는 3시간동안 잠들었고
I then went to sleep for three hours,
깨어났더니, 모든게
and when I woke up, everything seemed
정상이 되었더군요
back to normal.
그 시간 전부를벤 복구하는데 썼나요?
It took you all that time to reboot Ben?
벤이랑 일해 보셨어요?
Have you ever tried to work on that thing?
아뇨
No.
그 13시간 동안, 다른 일은 없었나요?
During that 13 hours,did anything else happen?
이례적인 일이라거나
- Anything anomalous?- Uh...
솔라 플레어와 관련된거나
Related to the solar flare?
전부 로그에 있는대로에요
Everything is right here in the log.
확실치 않은게 하나 있는데요
There's one thing I'd like to clear up.
보안 시스템은 세라핌내 각 구역을
The security system records each quadrant
감시 카메라로 기록하게 되있어요
of the Seraphim with banksof surveillance cameras.
짐작이지만, 응급 전원이
Presumably, they were up and running
바로 다시 켜졌을텐데, 영상은
as soon as that emergencypower kicked back on,
시스템 메모리에서 지워졌더군요
but that footage was deletedfrom the system's memory.
매달초 가끔
There had been several
임시 간섭 현상이 있었어요
instances of interferencein the months prior,
하지만 이정도 레벨은 처음이에요
but none quite to this level.
예전에는 만약을 대비해
In the past, what I had done is
영상의 복사본을 만들었는데
make a copy of the footage, just in case.
이번 경우는
I went to do the same thing this time,
영상을 복사하는 대신에
but instead of copying the footage,
사고로 지워졌어요
I accidentally deleted it.
그 시간의 유일한 기록은
The only record of that time
제 로그에 수동으로 입력된 거에요
is what I manually entered into my log.
이 에러는 완전히 제 책임이에요
I take complete responsibilityfor that error, sir.
뭐, 우리는 실수 안하겠나요
Well, sounds like we didn't miss much.
저만 굳어 있었나 봐요
Just me swearing at abunch of inanimate objects.
아직 의료 검진 보고를기다리고 있긴 하지만
I'm still waiting for yourmedical examinations,
곧 보게 되겠죠
but as soon as I've hada chance to review them,
그리고, 정신과 평가만더하면 마무리 되겠네요
and you complete a seriesof psychiatric evaluations,
기록에 넣을게요
we'll put this one in the books.
정신과 평가요?
Psychiatric evaluations?
이후 추가 미팅이 있을거고
Just a few meetings inaddition to your post-morts.
당신의 재진입에 도움될거에요
To help with your reentry.
작년 하몬 크래거의 사건이후
It's a change in agency policyafter what happened
요원 정책이 바뀌었어요
with Harmon Kryger last year.
끝내기 전에 주의 당부 드려요
I probably should have warnedyou before I brought you over.
뭐 관료주의적인거고
There's just as much bureaucracy
지금은 좀 더 사적인거죠
now that we're in the private sector.
시간 맞추려면,지금 나가셔야 합니다
Sir, if you want to make it,you'd better leave now.
외부 미팅이라서
Off-campus meeting.
돌아와서 좋네요, 몰리
It's a pleasure to have you back, Molly.
그리웠어요
You were missed.
감사해요
Thank you, sir.
어떤가?
How's he doing?
준비됐습니다
He's ready.
환영합니다, 야스모토 씨
Welcome back, Mr. Yasumoto.
세라핌에서 변칙적인것이발견됐습니다
We found something of ananomaly on the Seraphim.
변칙?
An anomaly?
다른 솔라 플레어가통신 시스템을 차단했어요
Another solar flare knocked outthe communications system.
크라이거 때처럼?
Like Kryger.
네
Yes.
하지만, 크래거때와 다르게
But, unlike Kryger,
13시간 동안의
we're missing the security camera footage
보안 카메라 영상이 사라졌습니다
for the 13 hours that followed.
우연으로 보이지는 않는군
That seems like an unlikely coincidence.
비행사가 연관된 것일지도요
Even more so if you knowthe astronaut involved.
몰리 우즈
Molly Woods.
사고로 지웠다고 주장합니다
She claims she accidentally deleted it.
안믿기나?
You don't believe her?
안믿습니다
No.
어째서?
Why not?
실수나 할 타입이 아니거든요
Because she doesn't makethose kinds of mistakes.
이것이 전부가 될 수 있어
This could be everything.
가까이 둬야 해
Stay close.
그래서 말인데
About that.
남편 존이, 오늘 이사회에서
Her husband John gave a presentation
프리젠테이션이 있었지만,거부됐습니다
to your board today,but was denied funding.
저는 ISEA 관련해서만 가까이 하지만
I can only do so much from the ISEA.
회장님의 손짓이면, 그 가족을가까이 두실 수 있습니다
A gesture from you couldput us closer to the family.
지켜보기도 쉬울거고요
It might make it easierto keep an eye on her.
이게 마지막이야
This is the last one.
Oh, wow.
존, 야스모토 회사로의 호출입니다
John, you havean incoming call from Yasumoto Corp.
우즈 박사님
Dr. Woods.
히데키 야스모토 요
Hideki Yasumoto.
와줘서 감사해요
Thanks for coming.
어.. 영광입니다
Oh, please. Uh, it's anhon... it's an honor.
제가 더 영광이죠
The honor is all mine.
오늘 내가 아주 중요한 미션이 있거든
I have a very important mission today,
네가 좀 도와줬으면 하는데
and I think you're just the guy to help me.
무슨 미션?
What kind of mission?
음.. 탐색
Um... it's a search.
무슨 탐색?
A search for what?
휴매닉의 목적을 확장시키려면
I realized that in order tofurther the goal of Humanichs,
진짜 인간 경험을 주어야 하죠
to give him a true human experience,
가족의 일원이 될 필요가 있어요
he needed to be part of a family unit.
가족을 위해서
To be raised in a home.
직접 받아들였죠
So, I brought him into ours.
와이프와 저는 불임문제로몇년을 힘들어 했어요
My wife and I struggledfor years with infertility,
결국에는 아이를 가질 수
and, eventually, we were toldwe would never be able
없다고 합의하게 됐죠
to have a child.
이건 결혼의 중요한 효과에요
That can have a profoundeffect on a marriage.
우리가 행복하려는데,뭔가가 빠진거죠
As happy as we were,there was something missing.
거기에 이단이 있는거에요
And... and that was Ethan.
그러니까, 휴매닉은무자녀 커플에게 치료제인 거군요
So, you see Humanichs as a curefor childless couples.
입양, 대리출산.. 옵션이 많겠지만
Adoption, surrogacy... thoseare all viable options...
Thank you.
모두가 적절한 것은 아니죠
but not everyone is a viable candidate.
사람들이 항상 필요로 하는건
There will always be people with a need
동반관계나 연결같은거에요
for companionship and... and connection.
이사회에게 더 말할 수 있다면
If your board had let mefinish, I would have told them
공허함을 채우는것은매우 중요하다고 말하고 싶어요
that filling that voidis way more important
공감서비스 술집을세우는 것보다는 말이죠
than building a moreempathetic service bar.
아마도 이러한 미래적 제안은
I'm sure you understand
많은 도덕적 질문을 키울거에요
that the future you're proposingraises great moral questions.
네, 하지만 큰 가능성도 키워요
Yes, but it also raisesgreat possibilities.
동의해요
I agree.
불행히, 장기적 관점으로 볼때야스모토 회사에서는
Unfortunately, the long-termprospects are too murky
이번 투자에 부정적이에요
for Yasumoto Corporationto invest in at this time.
이사회의 결정은 지켜질거에요
The board's decision will have to stand.
주주들에 대한 책임이 있으니까요
We have responsibilitiesto our shareholders.
그렇죠
Of course.
당연히 이해해요
Yeah, I fully understand.
정말 시간내주셔서 감사합니다
I... I really just appreciate your time.
하지만, 사적인 시민으로는
However, as a private citizen,
그런 책임을 질 의무가 없죠
I would not be boundby those same responsibilities.
어떠니?
How is it?
좋아
Good.
- 먹어볼래?- 그래
- Do you want to try?- Okay.
좋은데
Mmm. That is good.
내꺼 먹어볼래?
Want to try mine?
그래
Sure.
그게 더 좋아
I like yours better.
바꿀래?
Want to switch?
응
Okay.
실례합니다
Excuse me, ma'am.
- 이거요- 괜찮아요
Here you go. No, thanks.
이건 당신 겁니다
This one is for you.
계산된거에요
It's already paid for.
누가요?
By whom?
Uh...
갔네요, 미안요
He's gone. Sorry.
네게 무슨일이 있었는지 안다, 곧 보자
_
이리와, 가자
Come on, let's go.
엄마, 아이스크림 떨어졌잖아
Mom! You made me drop my ice cream!
그래, 이거 가져
Okay. Look, have this one.
그거 싫어
I don't want that one.
다른게 좋아, 이런거
I want another one... like this.
이것밖에 없어
Okay, this is the one you chose.
그건 싫다고
I don't want it anymore.
가자
Let's go.
- 다른 아이스크림 줘- 이단
- I want another ice cream.- Ethan!
지금 가야 돼
We have to go right now.
- 싫어- 이단
- No!- Ethan!
Ethan!
Ethan?
Ethan?!
Ethan.
찾았을때부터 이랬어
It was like this when I found it.
Your hair looks really pretty.
엄마 머리 진짜 이쁘다
왜 그러는지 모르겠어
I don't know what's going on with him,
내가 떠날때랑 달라
but he is not the same as when I left here.
안 그래
No, he's not.
나이 더 먹었잖아
He's a year older.
그런 말이 아니잖아
That is not what I'm talking about.
변했다고
He's changed.
자기도 그래, 그런게 삶이야
And so have you. That's called life.
우리 가족의 연속성이
That's the consequence of our family
오래 중단됐었잖아
being apart for so long.
재연결되는데 시간이 걸리는거야
It takes time to reconnect.
노력중이잖아
And I'm trying.
- 그래?- 그래
- Uh, are you?- Yes.
우리를 밀치는 느낌이라고
Because it feels likeyou're pulling away from us.
무슨일인지는 모르겠지만
I don't know what's happened, but
느껴진다고, 걔도 느끼고
I've felt it. And he's felt it, too.
네가 돌아온 순간부터 그래
Ever since you got back.
떠나기 전에도 쉽지 않았어
Well, it wasn't that easy before
당신한테처럼 쉽지 않다고
I left here. Not easy like it was for you.
우린 항상 다르게 느꼈어
We've always seen him differently.
난 아들로서 대하고 있어
I see him as our son.
나도 그래
And so do I.
하지만
But the way
오늘 날 보는데..당신도 봤어야 해
he looked at me today...you should have seen it.
꼭 날 증오하는듯 했어
It was almost as if he hated me.
당신 증오하지 않아, 몰리당신을 사랑한다고
He doesn't hate you, Molly. He loves you.
날 사랑하는게 아냐
He doesn't love me.
당신이 걔한테 프로그램한대로
He executes a seriesof commands that you've
명령을 실행하는거잖아
programmed into him.
행동은 마치
He approximates a behavior
사랑과 닯았지
that resembles love.
그건 사랑이 아냐
But that's not love.
어째야 하는지 모르겠다
I don't know what's going on with you,
하지만 당신도 알게 될거야
but you have to figureit out, because that kid
우리가 부모로서 있게 해준다는걸
is the closest we're evergonna get to being parents.
야스모토에서 펀딩 받았어
I got the funding from Yasumoto.
바로 시작할거야
We start immediately.
녹화 시작
Camera recording.
마커스
Marcus.
안녕?
Hello?
안녕
Hello.
도움이 필요하다고?
You need help?
도움
Help.
어떻게 해 줄까?
What can I do?
해
Do.
그래 괜찮아
It's okay.
그래
It's...
괜찮아
Okay.
It's okay.
몰리
Molly.
어제는 미안해
I'm sorry about yesterday.
뭐, 틀린말 한거도 아니잖아
Well, you didn't sayanything that wasn't true.
야스모토와의 이번 기회는..
This opportunity with Yasumoto,
이상적인 시기는 아니겠지만
it may not be the ideal time, but,
몰리, 우린 해낼 수 있어
Molly, if we can make it work...
우린 해낼거야
We'll make it work.
내가 축하한다고 말했던가?
Have I said congratulations?
아니
No.
축하해
Congratulations.
이런 확장 미션후의 재진입은
Reentry can be a challenge
도전이 될 수 있어요, 특히
after this kind ofextended mission, especially
배우자와 자녀가 있을경우는요
if there are spousesand children involved. So,
그래서, 기관이이 미팅을 요청한거에요
the agency would like usto meet for a few sessions.
이 사무실이 당신에게성역이 되었으면 좋겠어요
I want this officeto be a sanctuary for you.
당신이 어느것이든
A place where you can
모든걸 말할 수 있는 곳이요
talk about anything and everything.
이곳에는 동료이셨던
We didn't have this resource in place
크래거 박사의 자료는 없지만필요할 거에요
for your colleague, Dr.Kryger. We should have.
기관은 그의 정신상태에 대한
The agency believes a lackof attention to his mental state
관심 부족이 자살의 요인이라고생각하고, 나도 동의해요
was a factor in his suicide. I agree.
변화기에 관한 평가를 가지고
Why don't we begin with your own assessment
시작해보는건 어떨까요
about where you are in your transition.
기분은 어떠세요?
How are you feeling?
물리적으로요?
Physically?
무엇이든 말해보세요
Whatever you'd like to share.
물리적
Physically.
감정적, 정신적..
Emotionally, mentally.
Okay.
재생 시작
Beginning playback.
Harmon?
하몬?
나야
It's me.
나 진짜야
I'm real.
세라핌에서 본 것 같은게 아냐
It's not like on the Seraphim.
환각이 아냐
You're not hallucinating.
다들 네가 죽은줄 알아
Everybody thinks you're dead.
여기.. 오면 안됐어
I... I shouldn't have...I shouldn't have come here.
하몬, 말해줘
Harmon. Talk to me.
무슨 일이야?
- What happened?- Molly?
몰리, 저녁 다 됐어
Dinner's ready.
내가 찾아갈게
I'll find you.
그때까지, 조심해
Until then, be careful.
그들을 믿지 마
Don't trust them.
누구?
Who?
아무도
Anybody.
- Synced and corrected by oykubuyuk -- www.addic7ed.com -